本字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业用途
-=风软FRM字幕组=-
翻译:睿睿 多拉迕 vampire786
雨潇 菲尔坦奈尔
校对:青色的花
你是谁?
Who are you?
怎么回事?
What is this?
陛下 他是渔网捞起来的 渔网
Your Majesty, caught him up
in a fishing net. A fishing net.
陛下 他一直在讲故事
故事里...
Sire, he's been telling stories.
Stories that...
我们相信他找到了...
We believe he's found a...
庞德・里昂
(西班牙探险家 在寻找不老泉的路上发现了弗罗里达)
Ponce de León
说他找到了
庞德・里昂的船
Says he found
Ponce de León's ship.
- 或是一起行过船
- 不 我跟你说了
- Or sailed on it.
- No, I told you,
庞德・里昂200年前就死了
Ponce de León died 200 years ago.
好 但他就是因为找什么东西才死的
没错吧?
Aye, but he died searching
for something, didn't he?
不老泉
The Fountain of Youth.
你多快能起航?
How soon can you sail?
涨潮就行
With the tide.
加勒比海盗4:惊涛怪浪
看这里!
幸运草!
Over here!
Lucky heather!
海盗剑!海盗剑!
Pirate swords! Pirate swords!
海盗于今天处决
来看他被绞死!
Pirate's execution today.
Watch him swing!
海盗木偶!
Pirate puppets!
吃我一剑 你!
Take that, you!
快点 爸爸 要不我们就看不见绞刑了!
Hurry, Papa, or we'll miss the hanging!
这不是绞刑 宝贝 是公审
下午才是绞刑
It's not a hanging, dear, it's a trial.
The hanging comes this afternoon.
海盗今天被绞死!
Pirate hanging today!
来啊 往上来
Come on. Up you get.
挪过去 海盗
Move along, pirate.
或者我应该说 "海盗船长"?
Or should I say, "Captain Pirate"?
过来 过来 往上走
Come on. Come on! Up you go.
肃静! 秩序!
Quiet! Order!
肃静!
Quiet!
现在出现在法庭前的
Now appearing before the court,
这就是声名狼藉的邪恶海盗 掠夺者
the notorious and infamous
pirate, pillager,
- 还有强盗...
- 安静!
- and highwayman...
- Quiet!
...杰克・斯派洛船长!
...Captain Jack Sparrow!
我跟你说了 名字是吉布斯!
乔士米・吉布斯!
I told you, the name's Gibbs!
Joshamee Gibbs!
- 多少次才...
- 听到了 听到了!
- How many times...
- Hear ye, hear ye!
全体起立迎接 主持审判的
Presiding over these trials,
正义崇高的史密斯法官!
all rise and attend,
the Right Honorable Justice Smith!
尊敬的阁下
My dear sir.
安静!
Quiet!
好了...
Now...
...堂下是何人?
...what do we have here?
杰克?
Jack?
闭嘴!
Shut up!
我不认识他
I don't recognize him.
没这必要 你说什么?
Not necessary. You were saying?
我不是杰克・斯派洛
Jack Sparrow is not my name.
我叫乔士米・吉布斯!
My name is Joshamee Gibbs.
是这样么?
Is that so?
- 这里写的是杰克・斯派洛
- 我告诉他们
- It says Jack Sparrow here.
- I told 'em.
我不是杰克・斯派洛
我倒是很乐意在法庭上指证他
I'm not Jack Sparrow, who I would
be happy to identify to the court
- 如果那对我的案子有所帮助的话
- 这真是可悲的狡辩啊
- if it would help my case.
- I think that would be a poor defense,
除非你想像只大海豹那样被击倒
unless you want to be bludgeoned again
like a harp seal.
犯人声称自己
The prisoner claims of being innocent
不是杰克・斯派洛
你们的裁决如何?
to being Jack Sparrow. How do you find?
不公审? 但我们不是来这里检验证据的吗...
No trial? But aren't we here
to examine the evidence...
陪审团长 你觉得他有罪吗?
Foreman, your finding. Guilty?
有罪裁决意味着他要被绞死
Guilty verdict means he'll hang.
绞死他! 把他吊起来!
Hang him! String him up!
- 有罪?
- 这不公平!
- Guilty?
- That's not fair!
闭嘴
Shut it.
乔士米・吉布斯 你作为杰克・斯派洛
Joshamee Gibbs, the crime of which
you've been found guilty of
被指控的罪行是无辜的
is being innocent of being Jack Sparrow.
我在此减免你的判刑
I hereby commute your sentence,
判你无期徒刑
and order that you be imprisoned
for the remainder
在牢里度过你那可悲的 垂死的
水深火热的余生吧
of your miserable, moribund,
mutton-chopped life.
- 什么?!
- 绞死他!
- What?!
- Hang him!
- 绞死他!
- 就这样了
- Hang him!
- There.
- 胡扯!
- 吊死他! 吊得高高的!
- Balderdash!
- String him up! Hang him high!
之后会安排押送这名犯人
Means shall be arranged
to transport this prisoner
去伦敦塔
to the Tower of London.
非常感谢
Thanks very much.
谢谢
Ta.
快 滚上去
Come on. Get up there.
上去!
Get up!
该死的
现在我们都奔监狱去了
Hell's teeth.
Now we're both headed for prison.
别担心
我买通了马夫
Not to worry.
I've paid off the driver.
十分钟后 我们就到伦敦城外
马已经在等我们了
Ten minutes, we'll be outside
London Town, horses waiting.
今晚 我们就能到海岸
Tonight, we make the coast.
然后就只剩找艘船了
Then it's just a matter
of finding a ship.
- 全在计划之中 对么?
- 完全正确
- All part of the plan, yes?
- Exactly.
我今早才到达伦敦城的
I arrived in London Town
just this morning
为解救那个乔士米・吉布斯
和绞架有约的人
to rescue one Joshamee Gibbs
from one appointment with the gallows.
看见你现在还活着
Seeing as how you're still alive,
我得说至今为止一切都很顺利
I'd say it's all been
very successful thus far.
你怎么了 吉布斯?
What happened to you, Gibbs?
我以为你任职他处或是转行了呢
I thought you were employed elsewhere
or otherwise engaged.
是啊 但我总是像贼一样
偷听有关黑珍珠号的消息
Aye. But I always listened like a thief
for news of the Black Pearl.
没人知道她要驶向何方
Nobody's seen where
she might next make port.
然后 我听到谣传:
Then, I hear a rumor:
杰克・斯派洛在伦敦招募新人员上船
Jack Sparrow's in London
with a ship and looking for a crew.
- 我没有啊
- 但我听说的是这样
- Am not.
- But that's what I heard.
事实上 你今晚就要在
Fact is, you're signing up men tonight.
叫"船长的女儿"的酒吧签人
Pub called The Captain's Daughter.
- 我没有!
- 嗯 我觉得这事有点怪
- Am not!
- Well, I thought it a bit odd,
但然后 你从来都不按常理出牌
but then, you've never been
the most predictable of sorts.
告诉我
Tell me something.
是不是有人在借我的名字
在外面玷污我的名声?
There is another Jack Sparrow out there
sullying my good name?
- 骗子
- 没错
- An impostor.
- Indeed.
但是...是一个有船的骗子
But... an impostor with a ship.
需要人手
And in need of a crew.
此乃天助我也 我也如此
Which, as fate would have it, so am I.
你怎么样 杰克?
What about you, Jack?
上次我听说
你固执的要找到不老泉
Last I heard, you were hell-bent
to find the Fountain of Youth.
运气如何?
Any luck?
遇到了状况
我们不得不...
Circumstances arose
and forced a compelling insight
先英勇救人
regarding discretion and valor.
- 那就是说你放弃了
- 我没有
- Meaning, you gave up.
- I did not.
我只是和以往一样一心不二
极其确定
I am just as bent as ever.
Hellishly so.
我会尝到那些水的
吉布斯船长 记着我的话
I shall taste those waters,
Master Gibbs. Mark my words.
挺近啊
Short trip.
都在计划之中 对么?
All part of the plan, yes?
不对
No.
你就是杰克・斯派洛?
You are Jack Sparrow?
还应该有个"船长"
There should be a "Captain"
in there somewhere.
我听说过你
I've heard of you.
你也知道我是谁
And you know who I am.
看起来面熟
我以前勒索过你么?
Face is familiar.
Have I threatened you before?
在你面前的是乔治・奥古斯特斯
布朗斯维克-鲁纳伯格的公爵
You are in the presence of George
Augustus, Duke of Brunswick-Luneburg,
和神圣的罗马帝国财务大臣和选帝侯
Archtreasurer and Prince-elector
of the Holy Roman Empire,
大不列颠和爱尔兰的国王
还是你的王
King of Great Britain and Ireland,
and of you.
- 没印象
- 我得知
- Doesn't ring a bell.
- I am informed
你来伦敦为你的船招募人手
you have come to London
to procure a crew for your ship.
恶毒的谣言 不是真的
Vicious rumor. Not true.
那刚才你说你是杰克・斯派洛就是骗我咯
Then you lied to me when you
told me you were Jack Sparrow.
我是杰克・斯派洛
但我不是来这儿找人手的
I am Jack Sparrow,
but I'm not here to procure a crew.
那是... 别的人
That is... someone else.
别的叫杰克・斯派洛的人
Someone else named Jack Sparrow.
你们带错人了 害我白跑一趟了
You've brought me the wrong wastrel.
找到那个真的 把这个冒牌货干掉
Find the proper one
and dispose of this impostor.
不 等等 等等 等等 别急
No, wait, wait, wait. Hang on a minute.
我是独一无二的杰克・斯派洛
I'm Jack Sparrow, the one and only.
我是在伦敦
And I am in London.
招人手
To procure a crew.
准备起航去找
To undertake a voyage
- 不老泉...
- 什么?
- to the Fountain...
- What?
谁来把这些可恶的链子拿掉吧
Will someone please remove
these infernal chains?
来 来
Come, come.
我们知道你手上拿着地图
We know you're in possession of a map.
没收地图 然后绞了他!
So confiscate the map,
and to the gallows with him!
你有地图么?
Have you a map?
- 没
- 在哪儿?
- No.
- Where is it?
真话? 我弄丢了
The truth? I lost it.
- 事实上 就在最近
- 我有一份报告
- Quite recently, in fact.
- I have a report.
西班牙人找到了不老泉
The Spanish have located
the Fountain of Youth.
我不会让那悲哀的西班牙君主
I will not have some
melancholy Spanish monarch,
一个天主教徒 得到永生的!
a Catholic, gain eternal life!
你确实知道去不老泉的路?
You do know the way to the Fountain?
我当然知道
看看我
Of course I do.
Look at me.
你能带领一支探险队么
You could guide an expedition.
只要你允许 陛下
With your permission, your heinie,
你会给我补给 船...
you will be providing, then, a ship...
...还有船员?
...and a crew?
还有一位船长
And a captain.
下午好 陛下
Afternoon, sire.
容我大胆问一句
为什么这人没有被链子锁起来?
If I may be so bold,
why is that man not in chains?
他必须被马上锁起来
He must be manacled at once.
在我宫殿的中心? 他没啥威胁的
At the center of my palace? Hardly.
海克特
Hector.
很高兴看到一个海盗弃暗投明
How nice to see a fellow pirate
make good of himself.
海盗? 不对 是私掠船
Pirate? Nay. Privateer.
执行的是受吾王批准和保护的任务
On a sanctioned mission under the
authority and protection of the Crown.
可能吧 但首先
As may be, but first,
我那亲爱的珍珠号怎么样了?
what has become of my beloved Pearl?
我丢了珍珠号和我的腿
I lost the Pearl as I lost my leg.
- 珍珠号丢了?
- 是
- Lost the Pearl?
- Aye.
我奋力的保护她
尽管如此 她还是沉了
I defended her mightily enough,
but she be sunk nonetheless.
如果那艘船就这么沉了
你也应该和她一起沉了
If that ship be sunk properly,
you should be sunk with it.
巴博萨船长 我们每耽误一秒
西班牙人就甩开我们多一些
Captain Barbossa, each second we tarry,
the Spanish outdistance us.
我很有信心你会得胜还朝并被嘉奖
I have every confidence
you will prevail and be rewarded
你渴望已久的高位
with the high station you so desire.
- 能为您服务就够了 陛下
- 而你 先生 堕落了
- To serve doth suffice, sire.
- You, sir, have stooped.
杰克 你的时间不多了
Jack, our sands be all but run.
何不加入赢者的队列呢?
Where's the harm
in joining the winning side?
你也能和王公贵族接触
And you do meet
a nicer class of person.
我都明白
I understand everything.
除了那假发
Except that wig.
他要逃了!
拦住他!
He's getting away!
Stop him!
- 射他的头!
- 不! 拦住那海盗!
- Head him off!
- No! Stop that pirate!
下来!
Come down!
- 他逃了?
- 交给我吧 陛下
- He escaped?
- Leave it to me, sire.
守卫! 守卫!
Guards! Guards!
- 武器准备!
- 好 先生!
- Arms at ready!
- Aye, sir!
找到他!
Find him!
寻卫员 看守员!
Finders keepers!
在那儿!
There!
就完了?
Is that it?
停! 停下马车!
Halt! Stop that carriage!
射他的头!
Head him off!
让开路!
Out of the way!
拦住那个海盗!
Stop that pirate!
把路让开!
Move out of the way!
拦住那人!
Stop that man!
别让他逃了!
Don't let him get away!
开火!
Fire!
他要逃了!
追他! 拦住他!
He's getting away!
After him! Stop him!
追上他!
After him!
肮脏的海盗
Filthy pirate.
你好啊 小杰
Hello, Jackie.
你好啊 爸爸
Hello, Dad.
我听说你正在招人
I heard you're putting together a crew.
如果大家都这么说 那一定是真的了
If enough people keep saying it,
it must be true.
我知道你要去哪儿
不老泉
I heard where you're headed.
The Fountain.
你去过?
Have you been there?
你看这张脸像是去过不老泉的么?
Does this face look like
it's been to the Fountain of Youth?
- 这要看灯光了
- 儿子 去到那泉
- Depends on the light.
- Son, the Fountain.
需要有指定的物品
才能完成凡俗的仪式
There'll be items required
for the profane ritual.
两个圣杯
Two chalices.
- 在地图上画了圣杯
- 两个 银质的
- On the map there was a chalice.
- Two, silver.
来自于庞德・里昂的船上
你两个都需要
From the Ponce de Len ship.
You'll need both.
- 干吗?
- 做仪式 别当傻子 小杰
- For?
- The ritual. Don't be a fool, Jackie.
出海之前要找到所有的细节
Find out every detail
before you set sail.
哦 出海 我也想
Oh, set sail. Love to.
但那样 我可得要条船
But for that, I may need a ship.
那边那些伙计 他们有船
Those folk, over there,
they have a ship.
他们正招人呢
They're signing up sailors right now.
My heart is pierced by Cupid
I disdain all glittering gold
最后一件事 小杰
And one last thing, Jackie.
泉会考验你
记住我的话
The Fountain will test you.
Mark my words.
My heart is pierced by Cupid
I disdain all glittering gold
There is nothing can console me
But my jolly sailor bold
我听说你们正在招人
I hear you be recruiting a crew.
是啊 那是
Aye. That is,
杰克・斯派洛要准备远行
Jack Sparrow be putting together
a modest venture.
你挺有胆的啊 是不?
You got some nerve, ain't ya?
那么高调的穿成那样?
Turning up here dressed like that?
你是什么 什么冒牌货么?
What are you, some kind of impostor?
你知道我是谁么 哥们?
Have you any idea who I am, mate?
嘿 伙计们!
Oi, muckers!
这儿有个小子忘记自己的名字了!
There's a bloke here what's
forgotten his own name!
小伙子们 我和斯派洛一起出航
Lads, I'm sailing with Sparrow.
谁要给水手买杯酒?
Who'll buy a sailor a drink?
谁是下一个?
Who's next?
多给我们带点这样的
Bring us some more of those ones.
是啊 做四个吧
Yeah, make it four.
你偷了我的身份
我是来揭穿你的
You've stolen me,
and I'm here to take meself back.
别再做那个动作了
Stop doing that.
只有一个活着的人知道那招
Only one person alive knows that move.
早就想做这个了
Always wanted to do that.
你好啊 安洁莉卡
Hello, Angelica.
你好 杰克 大开眼界了没
Hello, Jack. Are you impressed?
我想我差点有一次或者两次
可以杀了你
I think I almost killed you
once or twice there.
我真感动 这是最真诚的恭维了
I'm touched at this most
sincerest form of flattery.
但为什么?
But why?
你是唯一我能冒充的海盗
You were the only pirate
I thought I would pass for.
这可不是恭维
That is not a compliment.
别担心 杰克
我很早前就原谅你了
Don't worry, Jack.
I forgave you a long time ago.
- 为什么? 离开你么?
- 记清楚是我离开你的
- For what? For leaving you?
- Recall that I left you.
一个绅士会允许小姐活在她杜撰的世界
A gentleman allows a lady
to maintain her fictions.
你看 斯派洛 只要我的水手们拿到钱
Look, Sparrow. As long as
my sailors get their money,
他们会愿意忍受任何的怪癖
they're willing to put up with
any number of peculiarities.
有一件事我不永远会忍受
There is one peculiarity
with which I will not put up with.
要冒充我 就要冒充成船长
I will be impersonated as "Captain."
Nothing less.
呃 那样的话 你需要艘船
Well, for that, you need a ship,
恰好呢 我有一艘
and as it turns out, I have one.
我是需要船
I could use a ship.
我听说你去过不老泉
I hear tell you've been to the Fountain.
最近有好多的道听途说啊
There be a lot of hear-telling
going on these days.
- 不老泉
- 最亲爱的安洁莉卡 不用怕
- The Fountain of Youth.
- Dearest Angelica, fret not.
你还有几年不错的光阴呢
You still have a few usable years left.
总是那么会说话
Always so charming.
你没回答我
You didn't answer me.
好 且不管那泉
浪费时间 真的...
Aye. Regarding the Fountain.
Waste of time, really...
夫人 我发现一个不像海员的人
在到处打探消息
Milady, I see unseamanlike fellows
of an officious-looking nature.
无耻的海盗!
找到他们!
Wretched pirates!
Find 'em! Maggots!
你的朋友?
Friends of yours?
我可能是无心的
得罪了国王或是别的谁
I may have unintentionally
slighted some king or other.
开门!
Open it!
- 是啊 你一点都没变
- 是说我要改变吗?
- Yeah, you haven't changed.
- Implying the need?
是
Yes.
开门 以陛下的名义
Open this door,
in the name of His Majesty.
你背叛了的
你勾引我还利用了我
You betrayed me.
You seduced me and you used me.
我当初对男人的花招都知之甚少
I was innocent of the ways of men.
你对付我这情场老手 也花招也不少
You demonstrated a lot of technique
for someone I supposedly corrupted.
快逃啊 这里 快 夫人!
Imminent danger. Here, now, milady!
打开!
Open it!
我都准备好我的誓言了 可你...
I was ready to take my vows. And you...
你跑去西班牙修院做什么?
What were you doing in
a Spanish convent, anyway?
我搞错了 以为是妓院
Mistook it for a brothel.
Honest mistake.
- 他在那儿!
- 就在上面!
- There he is!
- Over there!
我们现在不占优势
We are at a disadvantage.
说你自己吧
被你冒充的人可不觉得
Speak for yourself.
Unlike some who pretend to be,
但事实上 你连蜡烛都拿不稳
but cannot, in fact, hold a candle to,
我才是杰克・斯派洛船长
I am Captain Jack Sparrow.
你怎么能说我利用你?
How can you say I used you?
你自己心里清楚
You know exactly how.
我知道 但你怎么能那么说?
I know, but how can you say it?
- 怎么样
- 什么怎么样
- So, what is it?
- What is what?
不老泉啊
About the Fountain.
你知道多少
What do you know?
你不会恰好拿着
You don't happen to be in possession
两只庞德・里昂的银圣杯吧?
of two silver chalices,
circa Ponce de Len?
- 没有
- 哈 我就知道
- No.
- Thought not.
- 怎么了?
- 我听到一些故事
- Why?
- I hear stories.
谣言
Rumors.
你当然知道有仪式
You are, of course, aware of the ritual.
嗯 我知道
Yes, I am.
是什么?
需要带什么去呢?
What is it?
What is required?
一条美人鱼 杰克
A mermaid, Jack.
这绝对是个错误
There's been a mistake.
是无期徒刑 不是死刑 我不能死!
It's a life sentence, not death. Life!
- 巴博萨
- 谢谢 绅士们
- Barbossa.
- Thank you, gentlemen.
我相信你会打套索吧
I trust you can tie a noose.
那挺难的
That's a hard thing,
逼人给圈自己的上吊绳
forcing a man to twist
his own hanging rope.
自己种下的恶果得自己尝
You must lie in your bed
the way you made it.
你是怎么了?
What's happened to you?
- 杰克・斯派洛在哪儿?
- 他逃了
- Where be Jack Sparrow?
- He escaped.
我时间表很紧 吉布斯
I'm on a tight schedule, Gibbs.
皇家探宝舰队天一亮就要起航了
The HMS Providence
sets sail at first light.
如果你不想看它出发
就吊死在这儿
If you do not care to watch it
hanging here dead,
搞得满嘴的苍蝇...
with a mouth full of flies...
否则...现在就交代
...speak now.
带我跟你走吧
任何地方...
Take me with you.
Any point of the compass...
带你去哪儿 吉布斯
不老泉? 嗯?
Take you where, Gibbs?
The Fountain? Aye?
那是杰克打算去的地方?
Is that where Jack be headed?
你有什么能告诉我的 吉布斯?
Have you anything
you can offer me, Gibbs?
随便什么啊
Anything at all?
我明着跟你说吧
你别想看见黎明了
Upon me naked word,
you'll not see the dawn.
交过来
Hand it over.
- 你这蠢人
- 我有足够的时间
- You fool!
- I had just enough time
来学习这些阴间的圆圈
to study those infernal circles.
每条路线 每个目的地
都存在...这里
Every route, every destination.
All safe... in here.
欢迎回归皇家海军
吉布斯先生
Welcome back to His Majesty's navy,
Master Gibbs.
准备起航 水手
Show a leg, sailor!
遵命 先生
Aye, sir.
什么?
What?
- 这误会大了
- 继续走
- There's been a horrible mistake.
- Keep moving.
- 我不该在这里
- 很多人在海里醒来
- I'm not supposed to be here.
- Many a man's woken up at sea,
茫茫然不知是怎么回事
no idea what, when, wherefore or why.
完全忘记前晚签下合同
No memory of the night afore,
whence he signed up
然后把所有的意外之财全部拿去买醉
and drank away all his bonus money.
不 不 不 你不明白 伙计
No, no, no. You don't understand, mate.
我是杰克・斯派洛船长
独一无二的
I'm Captain Jack Sparrow.
The original. The only.
我是斯克罗姆 幸会 现在继续走
Scrum, and the pleasure's all mine.
Now, keep moving.
斯克罗姆
Scrum.
把你的胳膊肘收回去
Get your elbows in!
为什么有一具玻璃棺材
Why is there a glass coffin?
我看起来像管事的吗
Do I look like a man in charge?
- 我在哪里
- 抱歉 斯派洛船长先生
- Where am I?
- 'Scuse me, Captain Sparrow, sir.
十分荣幸地欢迎您
I be right honored
to welcome you aboard
登上臭名昭著的安妮女王复仇号
our world-renowned vessel of infamy,
Queen Anne's Revenge.
黑胡子的船
Blackbeard.
干活
Work!
- 他长得很奇怪
- 他是僵尸人
- He's a curious one.
- He's been zombiefied.
僵尸人
Zombiefied.
黑胡子船长干的
所有带头的都是
Blackbeard's doing.
All the officers are the same.
这样他们才更顺从
Makes 'em more compliant.
脾气暴躁嘛
And perpetually ill-tempered.
- 快点吧 用力擦
- 嗯
- Come on. Scrub.
- Yeah.
拉 拉 拉
Pull! Pull! Pull!
航行了五天 至少
Five days underway, at least.
对 你闻着海水的味就知道吗
Aye. You can tell that
by the smell of the sea?
是船员的臭味
Smell of the crew.
喂 那个倒霉蛋做了什么
Oi. What did that poor sod do?
我最好不要重蹈覆辙
And how can I make sure to not?
他吗? 他是个基督徒
Him? Churchly fellow.
总是念叨着万能的主啊
Always going on about the Lord Almighty.
是船上的狂热教徒?
Bible-thumper on this ship?
他以前是传教士
A missionary is his story.
我听说他在一次掠夺中被俘
What I heard was
he got captured in a raid.
船上其余人都被杀了
不过他没有
Rest of the ship got killed,
but not 'im.
大副不让杀他
First mate wouldn't let it happen
因为他之前是信主的
on account of his premier standing
with the Lord.
大副拼上她的性命帮一个囚犯
A first mate sticking her neck out
for some prisoner.
实在是太少见了
That you don't see.
"她" 大副是个女的?
"Her"? First mate is a "her"?
回去工作
Back to work!
平稳向前
Steady as she goes.
你是个冷酷 没有感情 难缠的坏女人
You are a ruthless,
soulless, cross-grained cur.
- 我告诉过你我有船
- 不 是黑胡子有船
- I told you I had a ship.
- No, Blackbeard has a ship,
现在我成了上面的囚犯
upon which I am now imprisoned.
我们做得到的 杰克
We can do this, Jack.
不老泉 你一直想找到的
The Fountain of Youth,
like you always wanted.
黑胡子 爱德华・汀奇
让所有海盗闻风丧胆的海盗
Blackbeard. Edward Teach.
The pirate all pirates fear.
闲着没事时让死人复活
Resurrector of the dead
in his spare time.
- 他会听我的
- 他谁的都不听
- He will listen to me.
- He listens to no one.
或许他听自己亲生女儿的呢?
Maybe to his own daughter?
女儿...他亲生女儿
Daughter as in... beget by?
失散了很久 最近才相认
Long-lost. Recently found.
她全身心爱着她亲爱的爸爸
Who loves her dear papa
with all her soul.
- 他相信?
- 我说服了他
- He bought that?
- I sold that.
然后他是为他自己找不老泉
Then it's the Fountain of Youth for him,
或者是为他和你 不是为你和我吧
or him and you, not you and me.
没错 杰克 最精彩的是
No, Jack, that's the best part.
他即将死去
He will be dead.
你要亲手杀了他?
You'll be handling
that part yourself, then?
有一个预言
There is a prophecy.
也许你不相信超自然现象
Maybe you don't believe
in the supernatural.
哦 不 我见过一两次这样的事
Oh, no, no.
I've seen a thing or two.
预言是这么说的
The prophecy is this:
黑胡子在两周内就会死
Blackbeard will meet his death
within a fortnight
死在一个独脚人的手上
at the hands of a one-legged man.
所以他才不是想要不老泉 杰克
That's why he needs the Fountain, Jack.
吉布斯先生 我们没有地图
Master Gibbs, short we are a map.
也许你能好心给我们指个方向
Perhaps you'd be so kind
as to provide us an heading.
做点好事 给我倒杯酒
Be a gem and pour me a gulper.
我们是私掠船 不是海盗 吉布斯先生
Nay. We be privateers,
not pirates, Master Gibbs.
我们以国王的名义做事
And in the king's name,
we behave as such.
遵命 船长
Aye, Captain.
我们在正确的航线上吗 吉布斯?
Be we on the proper course, Gibbs?
是的 航线正确 这就是证据
Aye, it be proper. There's your proof.
西班牙人
The Spaniard.
全体船员 进入备战状态
驶向迎风面
All hands! Battle stations!
Get to windward!
- 全体船员 迎风
- 准备开炮
- All hands, windward!
- Harden up two points!
- 准备开炮
- 大炮就位
- Two points!
- Cast loose the cannons!
- 炮手各就各位
- 就位 炮手准备就绪 先生
- Gunners, take posts!
- Take position! Gunners ready, sir!
- 出! 推!
- 等我命令
- Out! Thrust!
- Await orders.
稳住
Steady!
炮弹装好 等待命令 先生
Guns armed, awaiting orders, sir.
先生 下令啊 先生!
Sir. Orders, sir?
他连头都不转过来
He never so much as turned his head.
不老泉才是目标
The Fountain is the prize.
甚至都不愿浪费时间来击沉我们
It appears we be not even worth
the time it'd take to sink us.
现在我们落后了 全体船员 升帆
And now we've fallen behind.
All hands, make more sail!
全体船员 升帆
All hands, more sail!
全速前进
Ride hard between wind and tide!
先生们 我要说的是暴动
The topic, gentlemen, is mutiny.
最恐怖的暴动
Mutiny most foul.
是的 我是要来当杰克・斯派洛的水手
不是冒牌货
Aye. I signed up to sail
under Jack Sparrow, not some pretender.
还是个女人
And a lady, at that.
也没提到有可怕的僵尸人
And mention was failed to
be made of this uncanny crew.
我怕得腿都软了
Make my toes curl, they do.
我拿到了 全部
I got 'em. All of them.
- 干得好
- 好样的
- Well done.
- Good lad.
那么我说 黑胡子船长
On to it, then. Blackbeard.
- 他有什么习惯
- 他几乎都待在船长室
- What are his habits?
- Stays mostly to his cabin.
没错 差不多都待在船长室
That's right, mostly to his cabin.
- 好 不过当他出来时...
- 他根本不出来
- Yes, but when he comes out...
- He don't really come out.
他一定有出来的时候
He must come out sometime.
没有
Not really, no.
你们谁曾和他一起出过海吗
Any of you sail with him before?
- 不 没有
- 我从来没有过
- No, no.
- I've never.
完全没有
Definitely not.
- 你们有人见过他吗
- 没有
- Any of you seen him before?
- Not really, no.
只待在船长室 没人和他出过海
Stays to his cabin,
no one sailed with him,
没人见过他
no one's seen him...
好消息 先生们 这艘不是黑胡子的船
Good news, gentlemen.
This is not Blackbeard's ship.
这不是安妮女王复仇号
This is not the Queen Anne's Revenge.
不 这绝对是安妮女王复仇号
No, this be the Queen Anne's Revenge,
right enough.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
我看到了船的名字 在船后面
I've seen the name,
on the back of the ship.
先生们 大伙儿们
Gentlemen, sirs, fellow conscriptees...
你们被骗了
...you have been monstrously deceived.
- 我们被耍了吗
- 是的
- We are decepted, then?
- Yes.
你们都不知道此行的目的
You've nay been informed
of a destination.
死亡就在我们眼前
Death lies before us
当我们找到不老泉时
as we sail for the Fountain of Youth.
我们处境不妙啊 伙计们
It would be a sorry plight, mates.
- 死亡 确确实实?
- 黯淡灵魂的花园
- Death, for certain.
- The garden of darkened souls.
- 我们的生命将过早结束
- 除非...
- Untimely our ends will be.
- Unless...
我们夺下这艘船
...we take the ship.
那我们就夺下这船 就现在
We take the ship, then. Now!
行动吧
Go on, then.
- 帮我 伙伴
- 把它给我
- Help me, shipmates!
- Give it to 'em!
- 醒醒 这是我们的
- 快
- Wake up! It's ours!
- Come on!
起来 给我挪开
Get up! Off your backside!
- 你给我起来
- 把武器给他们
- Get off your fannies!
- Take it to them, lads!
快帮着我 打啊
Help me! Fight!
杰克
Jack.
如果这是个梦
你可以留着剑和靴子
If this is a dream,
you can keep the sword and boots on.
- 如果不是...
- 这是个梦
- If it's not...
- It's a dream.
不 这不是梦
No, it's not!
我认为我应该好心给你个警告
我们在夺船
I thought I should give you
fair warning, we're taking the ship.
不是针对你个人
Nothing personal.
如果你别插手
Think you might be better off
if you just...
会比较好
...stay out of it.
碍事
Boggit.
混蛋
Wretch!
你要么加入我们 要么就是敌人
You're either with us or against us!
我不加入 也不是敌人
I am not with you,
neither am I against you!
他这样可以?
Can he do that?
他是教徒 我想他必须这样
He's religious.
I believe it's required.
奋战到底吧 你们这些蠢猴子
Fight to the bitter end,
you cack-handed deck apes!
抓住他 把他绑起来
Take him, men.
Tie him down tight!
船是我们的了
The ship is ours!
先生们
Gentlemen.
我不明白了
I be placed in a bewilderment.
我在里面休息
There I were, resting,
突然间 我听到甲板上的吵闹声
and upon a sudden,
I hear an ungodly row on deck.
水手放下手中的活
Sailors abandon their posts
未经同意 擅离职守
without orders, without leave.
船桅前的那些人
Men before the mast,
就想要把船据为己有
taking the ship for themselves.
这算什么啊 大副
What be that, First Mate?
- 暴动 船长
- 再说一次?
- Mutiny, Captain.
- Again?
- 暴动
- 听到了
- Mutiny!
- Aye.
暴动
Mutiny.
暴动的下场是什么?
And what fate befalls mutineers?
大家知道答案的 是吗
Now, we know the answer to that,
do we not?
暴动者会被吊死
Mutineers hang!
船长 我想报告有人暴动
Captain, I wish to report a mutiny.
我可以指出是哪些人干的
I can name fingers and point names.
不需要了 斯派洛先生
No need, Mr. Sparrow.
他们都是小绵羊
而你 他们的主脑
They are sheep. You, their shepherd.
我有没有说过 先生
您的女儿有多可爱?
Have I mentioned, sir,
what a lovely daughter you have?
垂死前的灵魂最后的美景
A fitting last sight for a doomed soul.
别忘了 父亲 我们需要他
Remember, Father.
We need him.
如果我不时不时的杀个人
If I don't kill a man
every now and then,
- 他们就会忘了我是谁
- 懦夫
- they forget who I am.
- Coward!
他们没有忘记
They do not forget.
你的船员认清你是个卑鄙小人
Your crew sees you
for the miscreant you are.
懦夫 不管你杀多少人
A coward, no matter how many you slay.
今天第二次了啊 我又糊涂了
Twice in one day,
I find myself in a bewilderment.
你不是糊涂 是害怕
You are not bewildered, you are afraid.
你不敢走向正义光明之路
You dare not walk the path of
righteousness, the way of the light.
不是的 先生 情况其实很简单
No, sir. The truth is
it be much simpler than all that.
- 我就是个大坏蛋
- 这也对
- I am a bad man.
- That, too.
我也许也得杀你 传道士
I might have to kill you too, catechist.
- 不!
- 跟她的拉丁妈妈一样强悍啊
- No!
- All Latin blood like her mother.
爸爸 我求你
Father, I beg you.
我老忘了为何有个传教士在船上
There I be again,
forgetting why the missionary is here.
我女儿想拯救我的灵魂
或者是仅剩下的灵魂
My daughter fears for my soul,
or what's left of it.
你真的想拯救我吗 孩子?
You truly wish to save me, my child?
每个灵魂都能被救赎
Every soul can be saved.
真的吗 年轻的传道士?
Be that true, young cleric?
是的  不过 你估计希望不大啊
Yes. Though you I see
as a bit of a long shot.
但我仍为在这个地狱般得船上的
每个不幸的船员祷告
Still, I pray for every unfortunate soul
on this hell-bound vessel.
你能用你的信仰解除我的武装
You disarm me with your faith.
8声钟响!
Eight bells!
哪一个不幸的人在守了望台的啊
Which of you unfortunate souls
stood watch?
- 我 是我在守望
- 炮手
- I did. I stood watch.
- Gunner.
你吗?
You?
是
Aye.
是哦
厨子
The cook.
很好 把长船放下去!
Perfect. Lower the longboat!
放他过去!
Bring her about!
- 你干嘛要这样?
- 暴动的刑罚 法律解释得很清楚
- Why do you do this?
- Mutiny. Our laws be clear.
船长也能依法开恩的啊
Our laws allow the Captain
to show leniency.
我给过这个人机会决定命运
I have given this man
a chance to determine his fate,
不是每个人都有这样的机会
a gift not afforded to all.
该你了
Oh, you now.
给你个机会证明祈祷的作用
Chance to show the worth
of your prayers.
祈祷他脱离...邪恶?
Pray he be delivered from... evil?
定下航向!
Course made!
停 给他一个机会
给你自己...
Stop. Give that man a chance.
Give yourself a...
我觉得我最接近造物主是什么时候吗?
You know when I feel closest
to our Maker?
是当我看到苦难 痛苦和绝望的时候
When I see suffering, pain and anguish.
这时他真正的愿望才会显现
That's when the true design
of this world is revealed.
在苦难和悲剧出现时 他才会显现出来
And I see it revealed when in times
of hardship and tragedy,
他才会那些需要人恩施
kindness and compassion
are shown to those in need.
也许你该祈祷他不受伤害 对吗
Perhaps you should pray
for him to be unharmed, yes?
- 求求你 还有希望
- 再一次!
- Please, there's still hope...
- Again!
其实我对不老泉没有兴趣
I actually have no interest
in the Fountain whatsoever,
所以 如果你心意已定
so, if your heart is set,
你可以随便把我放在哪里
you may drop me off
anywhere you like.
可以了 舵手
That'll be all, Quartermaster.
你说的话像雾一样让我看不透
Your words surround you like fog
and make you hard to see.
那你呢 万能的黑胡子?
And what of you,
the mighty Blackbeard?
他们说 即便是被砍头 你的身体
Beheaded they say.
Still, your body swam
还是绕着船游三圈
然后爬上甲板
three times around your ship,
then climbed back onboard.
而你现在却在害怕地逃命
And here you are, running scared.
- 害怕?
- 怕去不老泉
- Scared.
- To the Fountain.
舵手有预知能力
The Quartermaster
sees things before they happen.
他预见我的死亡
所以命运开口了
He has foreseen my death,
and so the fates have spoken.
我的命数已定
The threads of destiny woven.
你对命运有点可笑的迷信啊 老兄
You have a ridiculously
high regard for fate, mate.
- 那你呢?
- 我?
- And you?
- Me?
我对算命这一套都表示怀疑...
包括算我自己的
I'm skeptical of predicting
any future... which includes me.
与命运抗争比较傻
但是我还是甘愿冒险
It'd be foolish to battle fate,
but I'd be tempted to cheat it.
我会找到不老泉 你带我去
I will reach the Fountain.
You will lead me.
那把刀就和你策划的暴动一样没有用
That knife will serve you no better
than the mutiny you devised.
暴动很有效
Mutiny served me well.
让我见到你了不是?
It gained me an audience with you.
是啊
Aye.
我警告你
To warn you.
你的大副
Regarding your first mate,
并不是她说的那个人
who pretends to be persons she is not.
继续说啊
Do tell.
她不是你女儿
She is not your daughter.
你胆敢这么说我的亲生骨肉?
You dare to speak
thusly of my flesh and blood?
先生 那女人骗术高超
Sir, the woman is consummate
in the art of deception.
我很清楚
是我不小心让她走上这条路
I know. As I mostly unwittingly
set her on her wicked path.
虽然我不能领功 说
Though I cannot claim credit
她天生会骗人是我的功劳
for her existing abundance
of natural talent.
安洁莉卡 我钟爱的女儿
Angelica.
My beloved daughter,
我这辈子做过唯一的真正的好事
the one true good thing
I have done in this life,
而你说 是你把她变成这样的?
and you claim to be the one
who corrupted her?
先生 她很邪恶的
Sir, what she is is pure evil.
比野兽还可怕
More to be feared than a wild beast.
又饿又有尖牙的野兽
Hungry wild beast with gnashing teeth.
来自地狱的饥饿野兽...
Vengeful, hungry from hell beast...
- 父亲?
- 甜美啊!
- Father?
- Sweetness!
没有必要伤害他 爸爸
No need to hurt him, Father.
他会帮助我们 对吧 杰克
He will help us. Won't you, Jack?
看见了吗? 即便是现在 她还是关心你的生死
You see? Even now,
she attends to your welfare,
尽管你一直诋毁她
giving lie to the claims
you make of her.
你会带我们到不老泉 对吧?
You will lead us to the Fountain. Yes?
这么说吧
Put another way.
要是我来不及赶到不老泉...
If I do not make it
to the Fountain in time...
...你也不能
...neither will you.
我马上就看这些航海图 好吗?
I'll have a wee look-see at those charts
straight away then, shall I?
先生
Sir.
- 什么事?
- 船长先生
- Aye?
- Captain, sir,
我听到不好的谣言 先生
I am unhappy to report rumors, sir,
船员都在传 是关于我们的目的地的
among the crew,
as to our destination.
闭上你的狗嘴 给我滚
Shut your trap and make way.
- 你想抗命吗
- 我无意冒犯 船长...
- That's the way of it, then.
- No disrespect, sir.
他们在怕什么 快说出来 讲
What do the men fear?
Say it. Speak the words.
白帽湾
Whitecap Bay.
是啊 白帽湾
Aye, Whitecap Bay.
每一个没用的水手都怕这名字
然后自以为是
And every worthless seaman
fears the name, and rightly so,
虽然很少人知道为什么
though few know why or dare to ask.
谣言是真的吗...
Be the stories true?
有话直说 吉布斯
Say what robs you of
your staunch heart, Gibbs,
不然就当你自己痴人说梦
or forever leave it
to the wider fields of fancy.
人鱼 船长
Mermaids, Captain.
是啊 人鱼
Aye. Mermaids.
海怪 恶鱼 特爱吃人肉
Sea ghouls, devil fish,
dreadful in hunger for flesh of man.
我们就是要经过人鱼海域
Mermaid waters, that be our path.
别丢了魂呐 吉布斯
Cling to your soul, Gibbs,
听说人鱼会把人吃到...只剩骨头
as mermaids be given
to take the rest...
...to the bone.
稳住 稳住 鼓起勇气
Steady! Steady, men!
Find your courage,
不然就准备面对恐惧
or be ready to purpose your fear!
自救啊!
Save yourselves!
- 有人落水啦
- 不 那是逃命的
- Man overboard!
- Nay! A deserter.
- 改变航向
- 不行
- Come about.
- Nay!
先生们  我不会要求你们
Gentlemen, I shall not ask
any more of any man than what
做办不到的事
但是我要问你们 我们是不是皇家海军?
that man can deliver, but I do ask this:
Are we not king's men?
是
Aye.
- 是不是执行国王的命令?
- 是
- On the king's mission?
- Aye.
我在经过我们的西班牙人眼中
可没看到恐惧啊
I did not note any fear in the eyes
of the Spanish as they passed us by.
- 我们难道不是皇家海军?
- 是!
- Are we not king's men?
- Aye!
是 准备 转向!
Aye! Hands all off, and bear away!
向白帽湾进发!
Stave on ahead to Whitecap Bay!
航向白帽湾!
Bear on, Whitecap Bay!
来
Come.
喝点小酒?
Little drink?
美酒 音乐 蜡烛...
Wine, music, candlelight.
这种事我们早就做过 杰克
I think we've traveled down
this road before, Jack.
是啊 没错
Yes, we have.
我记得很清楚
I remember it well.
弯曲 扭曲 转身 摇摆 翻滚...
Winding, twisting and
turning, gyrating, writhing.
再不停地翻滚
Incessant writhing.
记得圣多明哥吗?
Do you recall Saint Dominique?
马提尼克岛
La Martinique.
在圣多明哥我就想杀你了
I tried to kill you in Saint Dominique.
没所谓啊
Either or.
大副喝酒可不对啊
Hardly appropriate for a first mate.
我是你第一个吗? 我一直在想
Was I the first? I've often wondered.
你有求于人的时候的样子真迷人
You can be so charming
when you want something, Jack.
窍门是找出你想要什么
The trick is finding out what.
是真相 对不对?
The truth, then, is it?
黑胡子已经利用到了
Blackbeard has served his purpose.
我们俩去不老泉
You and I can go to
the Fountain together,
我们可以鸳鸯戏水
where we shall bathe one another
in equal shares of fame
尽享欢愉
and other assorted debaucheries.
而我会告诉你不老泉的仪式
And I'll tell you
the ritual of the Fountain.
是啊 淫荡的仪式
Yes. The profane ritual.
我能信任你吗 杰克?
Can I trust you, Jack?
- 我需要你支持我
- 最亲爱的安洁莉卡
- I need you on my side.
- Oh, my dearest Angelica.
我们是雌雄大盗啊 亲爱的
You and I are as
thick as thieves, love.
告诉我规则
Tell me the rules.
不老泉的泉水
Water from the Fountain of Youth.
人鱼闪亮的泪水...
The shimmering tear of a mermaid.
庞德・里昂的银杯
The silver chalices of Ponce de Len.
有了这些...
With these items...
- 怎样?
- 有了这些
- Yes?
- With these items,
你就可以汲取他人的寿命 杰克
you may take all the years
of life from another, Jack.
你知道那是什么意思
You know what that means.
你跟我 我们不能自己去
We cannot go alone, you and I.
仪式需要一个牺牲者
The ritual requires a victim.
- 这也太不幸了啊
- 是的
- That is unfortunate.
- Yes, it is.
我对不老泉越发没兴趣了
I find my desire for the Fountain
greatly lessened.
但是船上有你想要的东西
But there is something onboard
you do want.
黑胡子怎么办?
What about Blackbeard?
他在航图室 我们必须动作快
He's in the chart room.
We'll have to be quick.
他把每一艘船都留作战利品
He keeps each ship as a prize.
你帮我 我保证你能从中选一艘
You help me,
and I promise you your pick.
虽然我知道你会选择哪一艘
Though I think I know the one
you will choose.
瓶子里的黑珍珠?
The Black Pearl in a bottle?
黑珍珠怎么会在瓶子里?
Why is the Black Pearl in a bottle?
他在小模型里更讨人厌
He's even more annoying in miniature.
- 咱们成交了没 杰克?
- 安洁莉卡 我了解你
- Do we have a deal, Jack?
- Angelica, I know you.
你不会偷走一个无辜人的生命
You are not going to steal the life
of some innocent man.
那个独腿人的生命怎样?
What about the one-legged man?
我需要时间 杰克
I need years, Jack.
不是为我自己而是为了我的父亲
Not for me. For my father.
我真的是黑胡子的女儿
I am truly the daughter of Blackbeard.
你被自己的谎言给骗了 亲爱的
You've fallen for your own con, love.
不 他真的是我父亲
No, he is my father.
我跟你说的那些谎言 并不是谎言
The lies I told you were not lies.
你通过告诉我真相 骗了我?
You lied to me by telling me the truth?
- 是的
- 不错嘛
- Yes.
- That's very good.
- 我能这么做吗?
- 不论如何 我确定你会的
- May I use that?
- I'm sure you will, anyway.
当然了
Of course I will.
那你是不会放弃这个追求咯?
So, will you not give up this quest?
我想要个父亲 杰克 我没有过父亲
I want a father, Jack.
I haven't had one.
安洁莉卡 你的父亲 黑胡子
Angelica, your father, Blackbeard...
他是个魔鬼
...he is evil,
一有机会他就会杀了你
and he will kill you given the chance.
- 没人救得了他
- 你凭什么决定
- He cannot be saved.
- And who are you to set
谁能得救?
the limits on redemption?
你偷走了我的青春 杰克 你欠我的
You stole years of my life, Jack.
You owe me.
你这是在自寻死路
And you are en route
to getting yourself killed,
我不能袖手旁观
and I am not inclined
to stand by and watch.
白帽湾
Whitecap Bay!
所有人 上长船
All hands on deck!
Set to the longboats!
把船停好
Lay 'em out flat!
别乱了 为了我们娇艳的客人 弄得漂亮点
No tangles. Make 'em look
pretty for our dainty guests.
我们需要亮光 很强的亮光
We're gonna need light.
A lot of light.
走吧
Come!
闻到没有? 鲸鱼油
这东西烧起来就像神迹一样
Smell that? Whale oil.
Stuff burns like a miracle from God.
- 你能点燃灯塔吗?
- 英国人做的
- Can you make it work?
- Made by the English.
咱们还是别抱太大希望
Let's not get our hopes up.
夏天第一次新月旧月
The old moon in
the arms of the new one.
交替之时
First of the summer.
获取人鱼眼泪的最佳时机
Perfect for hunting a mermaid's tear.
我们死定了 他们会被人造亮光吸引过来
We're doomed.
They be drawn to man-made light.
- 鲨鱼?
- 比鲨鱼还糟 小子
- Sharks?
- Worse than sharks, boy.
一个时辰之内 人鱼就会被吸引过来
There'll be mermaids upon us
within the hour,
相信我  我们就是诱饵
you mark my words.
And we're the bait.
我听说 如果水手被人鱼亲吻之后 就不会被淹死
I heard it said a kiss from a mermaid
protects a sailor from drowning.
别傻了 人鱼都是雌性的 孩子
Don't be a fool!
Mermaids are all female, son,
像天堂的梦境一样美妙
and lovely as a dream of heaven.
但如果到了进食的时候
But when it comes time
to churn butter, so to speak,
她们会把水手从小船
they snatch a sailor out of a boat
或者大船的甲板上拉下去 为所欲为
or off the deck of a ship,
have their way,
然后这些水手就会被拉入海底淹死 被吃掉
and then the sailors are pulled
to bottom and drowned and eaten.
有时候 是反过来的
Or, sometimes, the other way around.
- 唱歌
- 什么?
- Sing.
- What?
他们喜欢听歌声
They like to hear singing.
我的名字叫玛利亚
My name is Maria
一个商人的女儿
A merchant's daughter fair
- 大点声
- 我离开了父母
- Louder.
- And I have left my parents
每年3000英镑
And 3,000 pounds a year
我的心被丘比特的爱神之箭射中
My heart is pierced by Cupid
我鄙视所有闪闪发光的金银珠宝
I disdain all glittering gold
除了那欢快勇敢的水手
There is nothing can console me
没有什么能够慰藉我
But my jolly sailor bold
我的心被丘比特的爱神之箭射中
My heart is pierced by Cupid
我鄙视所有闪闪发光的金银珠宝
I disdain all glittering gold
除了我那快乐勇敢的水手
There is nothing can console me
没有什么能慰藉我
But my jolly sailor bold
主啊 拯救我
Lord save me.
哎 看 看那儿
Man, look. Look there.
你会把她吓跑的
You'll scare her off!
是 那正好啊
Aye, and good riddance!
你会说话吗?
Can you talk?
会
Yes.
你好美
You're beautiful.
- 是你唱的歌儿吗?
- 是的
- Are you the one who sings?
- Aye.
你是我那快乐勇敢的水手吗?
Are you my jolly sailor bold?
- 是的 我是
- 斯克罗姆  你冷静点!
- Aye, that I be.
- Scrum, comport yourself!
兄弟们 我这短暂可怜的一生
Boys! There ain't much
been given to me
没有得到过任何有价值的东西
in my brief, miserable life,
there's the truth in it.
可我可以告诉上帝
But, by God, I'll have it said
斯克罗姆 得到了一个漂亮美人鱼的亲吻
that Scrum had himself a kiss
from a proper mermaid!
我的心被丘比特之箭射中
My heart is pierced by Cupid
我鄙视所有闪闪发光的金银珠宝
I disdain all glittering gold
除了我那快乐勇敢的水手
There is nothing can console me
没有什么可以使我感到慰藉
But my jolly sailor bold
所有的姐妹们 快来吧
Come all ye pretty fair maids
无论你是谁
Whoever you may be
只要你深爱着平息愤怒大海
Who love a jolly sailor bold
的欢快勇敢的水手
That ploughs the raging sea
我的心被丘比特之箭射中
My heart is pierced by Cupid
我鄙视所有闪闪发光的金银珠宝
I disdain all glittering gold
除了我那欢快勇敢的水手
There is nothing can console me
没什么能使我感到慰藉
But my jolly sailor bold
我的心被丘比特之剑射中
My heart is pierced by Cupid
我鄙视所有闪闪发光的金银珠宝
I disdain all glittering gold
除了我欢快勇敢的水手
There is nothing can console me
没什么能让我感到慰藉
But my jolly sailor bold
快看啊 开始啦
Out upon it! It has begun!
点火
Light 'em up!
勇敢点 把她们赶到岸边去
Muster your courage!
Drive 'em to shore!
撒网 快
Nets into the water! Quickly!
所有人 想活命 退到岸上去
Retreat, all, to land!
For your lives!
我说了 撤退!
Retreat, I say!
胆小鬼 回到海里去!
Cowards! Back in the water!
回到岸上也无法活命 我保证
There be no refuge on land! On my word!
来呀
我们抓到一个
We got one!
我坠入爱河了
I'm in love!
查查受伤的
Check the wounded!
看看能不能找到一条还活着的人鱼
See if you can find
one mermaid still alive!
来 搭把手
Come, give a hand!
干得好 水手
Well done, sailor.
大家都看到了吗
Did everyone see that?
我可不会再来第二次
Because I will not be doing it again.
回船上 找个安全的内湾 快
Back to the ship.
We head for a protected cove. Now.
- 上帝啊 这是...?
- 人鱼
- Lord. Is that?
- Mermaid.
- 赶紧回头是岸
- 回不了了
- Give up this madness now.
- I cannot.
你有没有在海滩上走过
Ever walk on the beach,
回头看到沙滩上双足的留下的脚印?
look back and see your footsteps
in the sand?
就跟这一样 只不过足迹
不在我身后在我面前
It's like that,
except the footsteps lie before me.
- 您是单足了
- 去白帽湾 长官
- Footstep, actually.
- Whitecap Bay, sir.
我们必须抓紧
We must hasten.
我们徒步前往的
吉布斯 给我指个方向
We travel by foot.
Gibbs, I require a heading.
- 但是 长官 船上还有人
- 他们已经死了
- But, sir, the men.
- They be dead already.
- 他们听上去不像是死了
- 哦 是吗
- They don't sound dead.
- Oh, is that so?
但我什么也没听到
除了海鸥筑巢的声音
Well, I hear nothing
but seagulls nesting.
你听到了吗 格鲁乌先生?
What is it that you hear, Mr. Groves?
海鸥...筑巢
Seagulls... nesting.
- 没有其他的了
- 方向 吉布斯?
- Nothing more.
- Heading, Gibbs?
上帝啊
My God.
不给方向 就要你命
Your head or my heading.
两个一起也行 我不在乎
I'll have me one or t'other,
I don't care which.
所有人 前进
All hands, forward!
- 交给你了 斯派洛
- 有必要蒙眼吗
- It's to you now, Sparrow.
- Was that really necessary?
最好别让你知道我船的准确位置
Best you not know the exact
whereabouts of my ship.
- 我是个谨慎的人
- 我也是
- I be a cautious man.
- So be I.
首先 我想找...
What I want first...
...庞德・里昂的船
...is Ponce De Len's ship.
为什么要带她一起?
Why is it we've got to bring her along?
因为眼泪无法保存 需要新鲜的
Because tears don't keep.
We need them fresh.
仪式怎么搞来着?
What is the ritual again?
不老泉水加人鱼的眼泪?
Water from the Fountain
and a mermaid's tear?
还有两尊银圣杯
And two silver chalices.
一尊有眼泪 一尊没有
One cup with a tear, one without.
这么说 两尊都盛泉水 其中一尊有眼泪?
So, one with a tear and water in both?
挺复杂的
Quite complicated, is it not?
两尊泉水 一尊眼泪
Both get water. One gets a tear.
喝有眼泪那尊的人
The person who drinks
the water with the tear
会得到另一个人全部寿命
gets all the years of life
from the other.
多少年?
How many years?
已经活过的
All the years
that they have lived,
和还能活的年头 如果命运仁慈的话
and they could have lived,
if fate had been kinder.
传教士
Clergyman.
万一我有个三长两短
On the off chance that this
does not go well for me,
我想在此声明
I would like it noted here and now
我已经充分准备好接受必要的信仰
that I am fully prepared
to believe in whatever I must,
以便得以进入
so that I may be
welcomed into that place
好人们才能到达的天堂 明白吗
where all the goody-goodies
get to go. Savvy?
教会管这事有一个词 杰克
你可以"皈依"
We have a word for that, Jack.
You can convert.
有需要再说吧
I was thinking more
of an as-needed basis.
舵手
Quartermaster!
- 怎么?
- 她不能呼吸了
- Aye?
- She cannot breathe!
- 她有水
- 她需要空气
- She has water.
- She needs air!
- 打开
- 她会逃跑的
- Open this.
- She will escape.
- 你们会害死她的
- 我支持传教士
- You're killing her.
- I support the missionary's position.
看到了?
See?
继续前进
Onward.
跟我想的一样 不是这边
Just as I thought. Not this way!
就是这边 对吧
This is the way, isn't it?
当然 但是我们该绕路从东边走
'Course it is, but we
should go around to the east.
那样就错过圣杯的地点了
That would take us out of
the path of the chalices.
- 那我们再绕回来
- 没时间了
- Well, then we'll circle back.
- There is no time.
是你坚持要带人鱼的
You're the one who insisted
on bringing the bloody mermaid.
- 那你玩暴动也浪费时间了嘛
- 你走路像姑娘
- Well, the mutiny didn't help.
- You walk like a girl.
- 到底谁像
- 必须有人去
- You would know.
- Someone must go.
你是说分头行动?
You mean split up?
你是说跳过去?我等不及要看看了
You mean jump?
This I cannot wait to see.
斯派洛去 找到船 拿回圣杯
Sparrow will go.
Find the ship, retrieve the chalices.
斯派洛? 万一他一去不回了呢
Sparrow? What makes you
think he will come back?
是啊 万一他一去不回了呢
Yes, what makes you think
he will come back?
我们不能相信他 父亲 我去
We cannot trust him, Father. I'll go.
她去
She'll go.
离不老泉还有多远?
How much farther to the Fountain?
我要没时间了
I'm running out of time.
大约朝北走一天 沿着那条河
About a day's march north,
following that river,
看到许多水塘时 就接近了
you'll get to a series of pools.
Then you're close.
你去
You will go.
我就知道会这样
I was sure it would come to this.
知道站在高处偶尔会有一种感觉
You know that feeling you get sometimes
when you're standing in a high place?
跳下去的冲动?
Sudden urge to jump?
我可没有
I don't have it.
我要圣杯
I need those chalices.
开枪吧 免得我摔死
Shoot. Save me the bother of the fall.
你去 再回来
You will go. You will return...
...否则我杀了她
...or I will kill her.
你不会杀自己女儿的
You won't kill your own daughter.
舵手 再给我六把枪
Quartermaster, get me six more pistols,
把子弹都清空 只留两把的
remove the shot from all but two,
但别告诉我是哪两把
but do not tell me which two.
你来选 斯派洛先生
You get to choose, Mr. Sparrow.
不
No.
- 是了
- 你确定?
- Yes.
- You're sure?
当然
'Course I am.
再来
Again.
拜托 肯定都是空的
Please, they're not even loaded.
再来
Again.
如果你真这么想看她死
If you're so keen on killing her,
- 不如让她跳?
- 什么?
- why don't you just let her jump?
- What?
如果你跳了 又死了
If you jump and die,
那就轮到她了
then she will have her chance.
再来
Again.
喂
Oi...
如果我跳下去 能活吗
...if I jump, will I survive?
娃娃
The doll.
- 是的 现在能活了
- 胡闹 我去
- Yes, now you will survive.
- This is nonsense! I'm going!
湿了 又湿了
Wet. Wet again.
我们继续 正北去不老泉
We go on.
Due north to the Fountain.
演得好 父亲
Well played, Father.
你知道哪两把上膛了 是吧
You knew which guns were loaded, right?
当然 亲爱的
Of course, my love.
有地图就好了
Be nice to have a map about now.
有船就好了
Or a ship.
停下 别动
Stop! Hold very still.
别让它碰你的皮肤
Ye dare not let it touch your skin.
怎么 老年人不能有点爱好吗
What? What be wrong with
an older man having a hobby?
还停着干什么 继续走啊
What are you stopping for, eh? Push on!
- 前进
- 死了以后有的是时间睡
- Push on!
- You can sleep when you're dead.
前进
Push on!
幸运女神继续眷顾我们
Fortune continues to favor us.
圣地亚哥号
The Santiago.
船长是著名的庞德・里昂
Famously captained by Ponce de Len.
没有其他人了
There's no one there.
好吧
Right, then.
不能停下
We must not stop.
你自己走
You will walk.
我走不了
I cannot.
不走就死
Walk or die.
手臂环住我
Put your arms around me.
- 我没要你帮忙
- 但你需要
- I do not ask for help.
- But you need it.
- 我们不是赶时间吗
- 别掉队
- We're in a hurry, yes?
- Do not fall behind.
停在这里 等我命令
Hold here 'til I say!
真美
Such beauty.
你一定是上帝的造物
Surely you're one of
God's own creations,
而且不是那些诺亚方舟上没有一席之地的
and not a descendant
of those dark creatures
可怕怪物的后裔
who found no refuge on the Ark.
真美
Such beauty...
...但致命
...and yet deadly.
- 致命?没有
- 你袭击了我
- Deadly? No.
- You attacked me.
不 你不一样
No. You are different.
不一样?
Different?
不是吗 你保护了我
Are you not? You protect.
难道你...?
Did you?
你把我从爆炸中推开了
You pushed me down out of the way.
- 看到不老泉了?
- 还没 不过接近了
- You see the Fountain?
- No, but we are close.
把怪物带来 蒙住脸
Bring the creature.
Cover its head.
她有名字
She has a name!
请指教
Pray tell.
她叫司瑞娜
She is Syrena.
庞德・里昂
Ponce de Len.
40个海盗40晚梦到的宝藏
If 40 pirates
dreamt 40 nights of treasure,
也比不上这间屋里的东西
it would not match
the contents of this room.
你
You.
- 你
- 不...
- You.
- No...
- ...你
- 我先来的
...you.
- I was here first.
- 你 为什么来这?
- 黑胡子派我来的
- You, why are you here?
- Blackbeard sent me.
- 你呢?
- 银圣杯
- Why are you?
- Silver chalices
- 给我的陛下
- 哦 得了吧
- for my royal liege.
- Oh, please.
后退后退 要保持平衡
Back, back! We have to balance it out!
船会整个滑下去
The whole ship will slide!
好吧
Right, then.
不如我们各选一样等重的东西?
What if we each choose an item
of approximately equal weight?
放回去
Put it back!
什么也别碰
We touch nothing!
那个呢?
What about that?
圣杯
The chalices.
喂 凭什么你先看
Oi! Why do you get to look first?
好吧
Fine, then.
- 一起
- Together.
石头
Rocks.
西班牙人
The Spanish.
他们抢先了
They're ahead of us, mate.
我要看一眼地图 如果是我担心的情况...
I shall have a look at that map.
If it's what I fear...
奇怪 为什么他们没带走
I wonder why they left this behind.
别碰地图
Don't touch the map.
他们认识路
They know the path,
不过我知道他们会在哪儿安营扎寨
but I can also see where
they'll most likely make camp.
杰克
Jack!
吉布斯 我正要去救你出狱
Gibbs, I was just on me way
to break you out of jail.
你偷了我的地图
You stole my map.
好了 可以开始了
Right. Best be started.
好
Ol?
人鱼
Mermaids.
小心 水塘很深
Careful, these pools run deep.
如果她跑了 就前功尽弃 舵手
If she escapes, all is lost.
Quartermaster.
看啊
Look. Look!
绑在这儿等死 被太阳暴晒
Staked out to die, to dry in the sun.
只有半身浸在水里 无法活命
Only half in the water.
Not enough to live,
但能延缓死亡速度
but just enough to make the dying slow.
好好想想
Think on it.
你的族人被杀了
就为了他们的眼泪
Your people, murdered,
harvested for their tears.
司瑞娜 你不想哭妈
Syrena, won't you cry?
所有人都会死 连你也是
All die, even you.
- 我听说快了
- 听着...
- Soon, I hear.
- Listen...
听着
Listen.
你听不到你的姐妹在尖叫吗
Can you not hear your sisters scream?
你没听到么
Do you not hear them?
我们只需要一滴眼泪
We need but one tear.
下等生物!
Vile creature!
- 把她的手指一根一根砍下来!
- 掐死她!
- Chop off her fingers, one by one!
- Choke her!
把眼睛挖出来取出眼泪
Cut out the tears
from behind the eyes!
你怎么不说话
Where's your voice in this?
也许等太阳出来她就会改变主意了
Maybe she'll have a change of heart
when the sun rises.
嗯 是的 她会被灼伤
但是我等不及了
Oh, aye, she will burn,
but I cannot wait for the sun.
也许我们应该烧死她
Perhaps we should build a fire.
- 不行
- 别反抗我 传道士
- No.
- Do not contest me, cleric.
- 你们不能折磨她
- 我们只需要一滴眼泪
- You will not torture her.
- We need only one tear.
如果有必要
我会把她身上的鳞片一片片拔下来
I will tear every scale
from her body one by one if I see fit.
如果这让你不快 一边祷告去吧
If that displeases you, go pray.
我错了 不是所有的灵魂都能得到救赎
你的就不行
I was wrong. Not every soul
can be saved. Yours cannot.
看啊 伙计们
一个曾经坚持信仰的人
Behold, gentlemen,
a man formerly of faith.
你口中的下等生物 比你好百倍
That vile creature, as you call her,
is worth a hundred of you.
哎呦 你关心她
Oh, you care for her?
你喜欢她
You fancy her.
我看得清清楚楚 不用否认了
And do not deny what is
clear to my eyes.
问题是...
Question is...
...她喜欢你么?
...does she fancy you?
我的天哪 她喜欢 我们走运了
By God, she does. We are in luck!
快流下眼泪...
Bring forth a tear...
...否则就见证这可怜人的死亡吧
...or witness the death
of this poor soul.
司瑞娜 如果你能落泪
Syrena, if you could manage a tear,
我会很感激
I would be grateful.
难过 那就对了
Sadness, yes,
- 但还不是悲伤... 还不是
- 爸爸!你不要动手
- but no sorrow... yet.
- Not by your hand, Father!
时间和潮水不等人
舵手
Time and tide wait for none.
Quartermaster.
啊 人鱼真无情
Aye, mermaids are tough.
真不简单啊
The lot of them.
像她们一样把她绑起来
然后把这东西丢掉
Tie her up like the others.
And get rid of this.
- 你有信心么
- 是的
- You are confident?
- Yes.
我是女人 她也是
I am a woman. So is she.
你在玩什么把戏 杰克?
居然跟巴博萨联手
What's your play, Jack?
Throwing in with Barbossa.
有个女孩...
There is a girl...
...一个女人... 异性
...a female... of the opposite sex.
- 你什么时候没有过女人
- 也许我应该说"落难少女"
- When is there not?
- Perhaps I should say "damsel."
你在救一个落难少女
好吧 这还是第一次
You're rescuing a damsel?
Well, there's a first.
是的 就是 我可能在很久之前
Yes, but it's just that
I may have caused said damsel
- 对这个落难少女造成了伤害
- 快说
- some manner of harm many moons ago.
- Out with it.
吉布斯 这是那个赛维尔女人
Gibbs, this is the woman from Seville.
啊 就是那个你假装爱她
然后离开了 伤了她的心的那个
Ah, you pretended to love her,
then you left her and broke her heart.
Worse. I may have had,
briefly, mind you...
更糟糕的是 我可能曾经有过
稍微的 怎么说...
...涟漪
- 涟漪?
...stirrings.
- Stirrings?
- 涟漪
- 什么?你的意思是 感情?
- Stirrings.
- What? Like feelings, you mean?
不不不 没到感情那种程度
更像是...
No, no, no. Not quite all the way
to feelings. More like...
好吧 感情 你个混蛋
All right, feelings, damn you.
但你还是离开她了
真卑鄙
And you left her still.
That's low.
谢谢
Thank you.
只可智取不要蛮干
Stealth over force.
考虑到你的情况 接下来就交给我吧
I'll take it from here
on account of your condition.
你的假肢没被白蚁蛀坏了吧?
You don't have termites, do you?
杰克 感谢你的关心
I appreciate your concern, Jack,
但我要一直陪着你
but I'll be keeping
you company all the same.
待在这里 指挥官
等我信号
Hold here, Lieutenant Commander.
Wait for my signal.
那里 那个人 他应该是头儿
There. That one.
That be the leader.
记住他的帐篷 因为那里...
Make note of his tent
because that's where...
不 等等 天哪
那一定就是它们了
No, wait. By God,
that must be them right there.
你的剑有股怪味
Your sword smells funny.
是的 涂了毒蟾蜍内脏的毒
Aye. Poison from the
innards of poisonous toads.
只要轻轻一划 几分钟之后你就死了
Just a scratch,
you're a dead man in minutes.
你介意把剑指向那边么
Would you mind pointing it
the other way?
我不喜欢蟾蜍
I don't like toads.
- 你在干嘛?
- 研究逃跑路线
- What are you doing?
- Planning an escape route.
- 你通常不都这么做么?
- 是的
- Isn't that how you do it?
- Yes.
但有时候我会... 随机应变
Or sometimes I just... improvise.
现在呢?
Now what?
我们就这么走出去 冷静 慢慢地
We stroll out, slow and steady.
像是自己人一样
Just like we belong.
- 司瑞娜 我很抱歉
- 菲利普 你还活着
- I'm sorry, Syrena.
- Philip, you're alive.
- 是的
- 你回来救我了
- Yes.
- You came for me.
为什么?
Why?
你是不同的 不是么?
You're different, are you not?
你不是很善良么?有同情心
Do you know not of kindness?
Compassion?
悲伤的眼泪 从来没有过
Tears of sorrow, never.
人鱼太无情了
Mermaids be too tough for that.
但欢乐的眼泪...
But tears of joy...
他们说这种反而更有效
They say these be
the more potent anyway.
司瑞娜 相信我 我并不知情
Syrena, on my word,
I had no part in this.
放了她
你们现在不需要她了
Let her go.
You don't need her now.
放了她? 不行
Let her go? No.
把她绑好
我们把她扔在这儿
Secure her bonds.
We leave her with her own.
逃跑路线是怎样的?
How's that escape route working?
现在是你随机应变的机会了
Here's your chance to improvise.
我也想呀
I'm attempting it.
我可能可以挣脱出一只手
I might be able to get a hand loose.
哎呦 你有刀 太好了
Oh, you got a knife.
That's very good.
还有更好的
Better.
我也要喝一口
I want one of those.
敬报仇 甜美畅快
Here's to revenge. Sweet and clear.
- 报仇?
- 别装了
- Revenge?
- Come, come, Hector.
如果你想要圣杯
If you wanted the chalices,
你已经知道它们被拿走了
you'd seen they were missing and gone.
你只是在坐等黑胡子
You were lying in wait, for Blackbeard.
乔治王 私掠船 假发
King George. Privateer. Wig.
演得太假了
Cheap theatrical facade.
- 我才不信
- 那个晚上你不在场
- I'm not buying it.
- You weren't there that night.
- 黑珍珠号丢了的那晚?
- 被抢走了 不是丢了
- When the Pearl was lost?
- Taken, not lost.
我们刚离开海地岛海岸就被攻击了
We were off the coast of Hispaniola
when we came under attack.
没有挑衅 没有警告
也没有谈判的机会
No provocation nor warning
nor offer of parley.
我们被炮火攻击
We were peppered with cannon fire.
然后黑珍珠号下方的海水开始变浑浊
And then the sea beneath
the Pearl began to roil.
船晃得很厉害
The Pearl was pitching
and yawing violently.
每个木板 每个栏杆
Every plank, every rail,
每个侧板 同时开始吱吱作响
every spar, all at once,
began to creak.
船上的缆绳像有生命一样
The rigging had come to life.
我们的船居然跟我们自己作对...
Our own ship turned against us...
...绑着我们的船员
像蛇一样绑着他们
...tangling the crew,
wrapping around 'em like snakes.
还缠上了我的腿
And wrapping around me leg.
但我的手是自由的 手里还握着剑
But me arms were free
and me sword was to hand.
我才是船的主人 不是黑胡子
I am the master of me ship,
not Blackbeard.
我是自己命运的主人 不是黑胡子
I am the master of my fate,
not Blackbeard.
所以我做了我需要做的事
So I did what needed done.
我活下来了
I survived.
所以... 你不是冲着泉水去的
So... you're not after the Fountain.
我才不管乔治王
或是什么乱七八糟的谣言
I care not for King George
or tavern yarns
说可以治愈四肢
that give hope for a healed limb.
我甚至愿意牺牲我的左手
换取杀了黑胡子的机会
But I'd give my left arm
for a chance at Blackbeard.
- 不是你的右手
- 我需要我好用的手
- Not your right?
- I need me good arm
用毒箭剑穿他的心脏
to drive my poisoned blade
through his heart.
伙计 你会有机会的
I'll see you get the chance, mate.
囚犯要逃跑啦
The prisoner's escaping.
他要跑了!散开! 找到他!
He's escaping!
Fan out! Find him!
走!快走!
Go! Go!
别开枪!我要抓活的!
Hold your fire! I want him alive!
我觉得那就是你的信号了
I figured that was the signal.
- 走! 准备出发!
- 敌人很快就会找到我们
- Go! Prepare to move out!
- The enemy is soon upon us.
杰克 抱歉没拿到圣杯
但我在赶时间
I'm sorry about the chalices, Jack,
but I've an appointment to keep.
- 我不会回去拿的
- 没这个必要
- I'll not be going back.
- No need.
- 要不要来一杯?
- 我们去不老泉喝
- Shall we have a drink?
- We'll drink at the Fountain.
为什么我们每次见面
你都是拿着什么东西指着我?
How is it we can never meet
without you pointing something at me?
斯派洛 你拿到圣杯了么?
You brought the chalices, Sparrow?
是的 喂!
Aye. Oi!
- 你还带了个朋友
- 是的
- I see you brought a friend.
- I did.
那个独腿男人也在附近 是吧?
And the one-legged man, he is near.
Aye?
是
Aye.
好了...
Now...
在我把它们给你之前我有一两个条件
Before I go just handing them over,
I do have one or two conditions.
- 说
- 首先
- Name them.
- Firstly,
把我的指南针还我
不 不 那是其次
I'll be having me compass back.
No, no, that's secondly.
首先 你得遵守承诺
Firstly, upon your word,
不能伤害安洁莉卡
you will bring no harm to Angelica.
斯派洛 我不想做任何对你有益的承诺
I'll make no vows
to the likes of you, Sparrow.
但承认我根本就不想伤害她
But it costs me nothing to admit
对我并没有任何损失
that she was never in harm's way.
那么其次 比首先更重要的是
Secondly then, priorly firstly,
把我的指南针还我
I will be having me compass back.
拜托了? 那是我应得的
Please? I do deserve it.
你知道抓住那只死肥猪有多难么?
Do you have any idea how difficult
it was to catch that filthy pig?
不是那个大只的 那个四条腿的
Not the big one,
the four-legged one.
谢谢 第三 胡子先生
Thank you. And thirdly, Mr. Beard,
我有的时候 虽然不是很经常
there are times, not very often,
也会反省我犯下的恶行
when I do reflect
upon my heinous misdeeds.
首当其冲就是
我有多么对不起吉布斯先生
Chief among them, I note how poorly
I have treated Mr. Gibbs,
- 我忠诚的大副
- 对啊! 现在你才想起这茬...
- my loyal first mate.
- Aye! Now you bring it up...
我让他在监狱中腐烂
根本不在乎他
Left him to rot in jail, I did.
Didn't care.
现在也不 但重点是
你得放他走
Still don't. But, point being,
you must let him go free.
- 就这样?
- 是的
- Is that it?
- I think so.
快决定吧 不然猪就要跑了
你们得自己去找圣杯 祝你们好运
Quick, or the pig runs,
and good luck getting those chalices.
杰克 如果是你 我一定会...
Jack, if it's all the same to you,
I'd be just as...
好的
Done.
放了那头猪
Release the swine.
其实如果你们不介意
我可以跟你们一段...
Perhaps, if you don't mind,
I could tag along with you folk for a...
伙计 这会指引你奔向自由
This will lead you to freedom, mate.
我发誓应该就在这附近
I could have swore it was
somewhere right around here.
我们不能停下
We must not stop.
死路
Dead end.
Dead. End.
死路
Dead end.
杰克 我开始有种
你不知道自己在往哪儿走的感觉
Jack, I'm starting to think
you don't know where you're going.
大家都说旅程比目的地更重要
It is not the destination
so much as the journey, they say.
拜托把圣杯给我
Chalices, if you please.
后退
Stand back.
杰克...
Jack...
...你有没有 真的...
...have you ever, in fact...
...亲眼见到...不老泉?
...seen with your own eyes...
the Fountain of Youth?
抱歉 你能重复一遍你的问题么?
I'm sorry, could you
repeat the question, please?
舵手
Quartermaster.
不 不!
No, no!
等等 等等!
Wait, wait! Wait.
"生命...之水"
"Aqua... de Vida."
斯克鲁姆先生...
Master Scrum...
- 你可不可以...?
- 阁下?
...do you mind?
- Squire?
真漂亮
So beautiful.
斯派洛 我要成为第一个尝泉水的人
Sparrow, I'll be the first
to taste those waters.
爸爸
Father.
独腿男人
The one-legged man.
- 你带他来了
- 我会这么做么?
- You brought him here.
- Would I do that?
爱德华・汀奇!
Edward Teach!
你在公海上犯下的罪
For crimes committed on the high seas,
我以国王陛下授予我的权力...
by the authority granted me
by His Majesty the King...
...伴随着很大一部分的个人成就感...
...and with a goodly amount
of personal satisfaction...
...我宣布你现在将被法院拘留
...I hereby place you
in the custody of the court,
成为我的囚犯
and declare you to be my prisoner.
我玩完了 是吧?
My trick's out, is that it?
所犯的罪行包括但不局限于
海上抢劫 叛国
Such crimes do include, but are not
limited to, piracy, treason,
谋杀 还有最恶劣的是虐待
murder, torture of
the most heinous sort,
包括残忍的偷盗了一只
用过的扭曲的多毛的右脚
including the brutal theft of one used,
twisted, hairy right leg.
你... 敢与此剑为敌?
You... dare face this sword?
离你的船这么远的地方? 当然
This far away from your ship? Aye.
嗯 我感到我颈后命运的冷酷呼吸
Aye. That be the cold breath
of fate I feel down my nape.
但我将以主之名最后一战
But I'll have one last fight, by God.
杀了他们!
Kill 'em all!
稍等一下
Hang on a minute.
我... 我想弄明白点事情
I just... I just need
to understand something.
好吧 所以 你们要打他们
Right, so, you will fight against them,
他们要打你们
they will fight against you.
只因为他想杀他?
All on account of him
wanting to kill him?
有道理么? 就是说嘛
Where is the sense? Exactly.
要我说 让他们俩自己打去
I say, let them fight
each other while we lay back,
而我们就靠边看着 喝点小酒
赌赌输赢!
watch, have a drink,
place some wagers!
好啊
Aye.
- 杀了他们!
- 绝不留情!
- Kill 'em!
- No quarter!
滚开!
Get off me!
斯克鲁姆 圣杯!
Scrum, the chalices!
还有眼泪! 跟我来!
And the tear! Follow!
打啊!
Fight!
交出来 人鱼的眼泪
这才是好孩子
Hand it over. The tear.
There's a good lad.
比起你 我更怕她
I'm more afraid of her
than I am of you.
交出来
这才是好孩子
Hand it over.
There's a good lad.
- 拜托把圣杯给我
- 杰克 抱歉
- The chalices, if you please.
- Sorry, Jack.
我告诉过你 我需要多点寿命
现在 用你的就可以了
I told you, I need years.
And now, yours will do.
斯克鲁姆!
Scrum!
司瑞娜...
Syrena...
主啊 你不能带她走
Oh God, you will not take her.
如果你带走了她 请让她回来
If you have taken her,
you will give her back.
让她回来...
Give her back...
让她回来 拜托
Give her back, please. Please.
我还以为命运会让我多打一会儿呢 嗯?
I expected fate
to put up more of a fight, eh?
我把你打倒了 如果是我就笑不出来了
I will not have that smile
on your face as I strike you down.
看看吧 爱德华・汀奇
Take a gander, Edward Teach.
这片土地将永远属于光荣的
This land is hereby forever
claimed in the glorious name
乔治王陛下名下...
of His Majesty King George...
来人呐 记下这人的勇敢
Someone make a note
of that man's bravery.
女士 请把圣杯给我
Seorita, the chalices, por favor.
只有上帝才能赐予永恒的生命
而不是这异教的水
Only God can grant eternal life,
not this pagan water.
来人 把这亵渎神的庙毁掉!
Men, destroy this profane temple!
不老泉!
The Fountain!
你个白痴
You are a fool.
你在这里所寻找的东西
只有信仰才能给你
You seek in this place
what only faith can provide.
信仰?
信仰给你光明让你看见
Faith? In faith,
there is light enough to see
却也足够黑暗让你失明
but darkness enough to blind.
这是为什么?
What devilry is this?
- 这是为了黑珍珠号
- 你做了什么?
- For the Pearl.
- What have you done?
安洁莉卡! 不要! 剑上有毒!
Angelica! Don't! It's poison!
如果不是有点毒液优势
I'm not such the fool
to take on Blackbeard
我才不会蠢到去单挑黑胡子
without a little venomous advantage.
杰克!
Jack!
我宣布黑胡子的船和船员
I claim Blackbeard's ship and crew,
以及这把剑
是对我失去的肢体的赔偿!
and this sword,
payment for my missing limb!
抓好了! 拉!
Hang on! Pull!
别浪费了我的眼泪
Do not waste my tear.
喝下它 这杯是有眼泪的
Drink this.
This one has the tear.
- 你得喝下另一杯
- 不!
- You must drink the other.
- No!
我没办法同时救你们俩
你们中有一个人得牺牲自己
I cannot save you both.
One of you must sacrifice.
爸爸 你喝吧 以拯救你的灵魂
You take it, Father, for your soul.
汀奇船长
她快死了 你得救救你女儿
Captain Teach, she's dying.
You must save your daughter.
这杯是夺去生命的?
This one takes life?
这杯有眼泪是赐予生命的?
This one has the tear and gives life?
是的 快啊!
Aye, hurry!
安洁莉卡...
救救我 我的孩子
Angelica...
Save me, my child.
不
No.
爸爸 我爱你
I love you, Father.
等等
Wait a minute.
事实上 可能搞反了
In fact, it might have been
the other way around.
这杯有眼泪 那个是另一杯
This cup had the tear,
that one had the other bit.
骗子!
Trickster!
- 恶魔!
- 爸爸!
- Devil!
- Father!
你个混蛋! 你怎么能这样?
You bastard! How could you?
你爸爸救了你
Your father saved you.
他的灵魂也许这样就能被救赎了 恩?
Perhaps his soul is now redeemed, eh?
你受伤了
You are hurt.
只是身体上
In body only.
我的心很平静... 因为你
My mind is at peace...
because of you.
- 我?
- 是的
- Me?
- Yes.
我迷失过
I was lost.
那海风 那潮汐...
The wind, the tides...
...它们本会改变一个人的信仰
...they ought to renew a man's faith.
但对于我来说 只有你能
But for me, only you.
菲利普 我可以救你
Philip, I can save you.
你只需要开口
You need only ask.
- 我只追寻一件事
- 什么?
- I seek but one thing.
- What is that?
原谅
Forgiveness.
如果不是因为我 你根本不会被抓
If not for me, you would
never have been captured.
开口吧
Ask.
原谅我?
Forgive me?
我恨你
I hate you.
救了你一命的家伙?
The bloke who saved your life?
我拥有的寿命是从我亲生父亲那里偷来的!
The years I possess,
stolen from my own father!
我只是帮了黑胡子做了
任何父亲都会做的事
I only helped Blackbeard do what
any father should have done.
你既残忍又无知
You are cruel and ignorant.
一把手枪 一颗子弹
One pistol, one shot.
在我饿死前自杀?
To kill myself before I starve?
亲爱的 我不相信你
There's no trusting you, love.
再说了 这是繁忙的贸易路线
Besides, this is a
well-traveled trade route.
你可以给过往船只打信号
You can signal a passing ship.
或是饮弹自尽 随你便
Or you can just bite the
proverbial bullet, as it were.
那我又要怎么挣脱这些绳索?
And how will I get free
of these bonds?
你半个小时之前就挣脱了绳索
You broke free of your bonds
half an hour ago,
只是在等着突袭的最佳时刻
waiting for the precise moment
to pounce.
杰克 承认吧
Admit it, Jack.
- 你还爱我
- 如果你有个姐妹和一条狗
- You still love me.
- If you had a sister and a dog,
我会选择那条狗
I'd choose the dog.
宝藏!有个装满珠宝的箱子!
Treasure!
There is a chest with jewels!
拥有控制风和潮汐的力量的珠宝!
Jewels with the power
to rule the wind and tide!
- 你在胡编乱造!
- 等等...
- You're making that up!
- Wait...
我怀孕了 你的
I am with child. Yours.
我不记得我们曾经...
I don't recall that we ever had...
- 你当时醉了!
- 我从没有那么醉过
- You were drunk!
- I've actually never been that drunk.
等等!
Wait!
我有话想对你说
There is something I want to say to you.
从我们一见面起我就想说
Something I wanted to say
from the moment we first met.
说吧
Go on, then.
我爱你
I love you.
我也是
As do I.
一直是 永远也会是
Always have. Always will.
我得走了
I gotta go.
杰克!
Jack!
还没完呢!
This is not over!
杰克!
Jack!
打偏了!
Missed!
复仇成功
The Revenge is mine.
先生...
Sir...
我们在甲板下找到了这个
We found this below decks.
所有人!顺风而上!
All hands!
Ply to windward!
动作快点 你们这些人渣!
Get cracking,
ye blooming cockroaches!
王室对我不薄
The Crown served me well.
但现在 以海神和天空之神之名...
But now, by the gods of sea and sky...
...朝托尔图加出发!
...make way for Tortuga!
吉布斯 你个混蛋 痴迷的老水手
你来了!
Gibbs, you filthy, besotted shellback,
you made it!
是!
Aye!
我相信我们联手
And I trust we managed a profit
- 得到了点好处?
- 好好看清楚
- from our joint enterprise?
- Feast your eyes.
指南针直指向目标
The compass led me straight and true.
黑胡子那些看船的家伙们呢?
What of Blackbeard's men
guarding the ship?
我用了跟新几内亚那次一样的招数
I employed the selfsame maneuver
we perfected in New Guinea.
扔下整艘船其实挺可惜的
Seemed a shame to leave
an entire fleet behind.
是挺可惜的
Shame indeed.
我恨那只猴子
I hate that monkey.
所以 黑珍珠号...
我们应该怎样把她弄出来呢?
So, the Pearl...
Any idea how to get her out?
我们需要一把十字弓
一个沙漏 三只羊
We shall need a crossbow,
an hourglass, three goats.
我们中得有人学会吹小号
同时另一个人这样子...
One of us must learn to play the trumpet
whilst the other one goes like this...
- 我认识一个有羊的人
- 很好 我可以这样子
- I know a man with a goat.
- Good. I can go like this.
杰克 我想问...
Jack, I have to ask...
你当时有圣杯 泉水和眼泪...
You had the chalices,
the water, the tear...
也许你能永远不老
You could have lived maybe forever.
吉布斯 不老泉确实会测试你
The Fountain does test you, Gibbs.
但最好还是不要知道自己的
最后一刻是什么时候
But better to not know
which moment may be your last.
生命的每一刻
Every morsel of your entire being
都是无止尽的奥秘
alive to the infinite mystery of it all.
再说了 谁说我不会不老?
And who's to say
I won't live forever, eh?
我发现了不老泉呢
Discoverer of the Fountain of Youth.
一切都充满不确定性 吉布斯
I have no say in it, Gibbs.
那才是我要的海盗生涯
It's a pirate's life for me.
懂了么?
Savvy?
FRS时间轴招聘群号：37304379
FRM翻译组招聘邮箱：frzhaopin2@gmail.com
与最新美剧亲密接触 享受海量FTP下载
风软FRM字幕组作品
-==http://www.1000fr.net==-
欢迎加入